hey hey what's up my friend so you're
watching this video now because you
might be thinking man Raina should I
quit my job to trade full-time now for
most of you watching this video I can
dare say you know 80% or more of you
watching this video the answer is no
right because you don't have what it
takes let me explain imagine this
imagine you want to earn $50,000 a year
from Trading some of you could be
wanting more some of you might be
thinking man Raina $50,000 is really
awesome right you know I only for 10,000
whatever let's just say it's $50,000 and
let's say your trading strategy on
average makes about 20% a year how much
Capital do you need right to get this
$50,000 a year on average return well
the formula is very simple you take what
you aspire to make in a year in this
case is $50,000 you divide it by your
average annual return which is 0.2 and
you get about
$250,000 that's the amount of capital
that you must have in your trading
account okay to make an average of of
$50,000 a year if you don't trust my
math you can just take $250,000 multiply
by 20% and you get
$50,000 back this figure that you dream
of yeah that you aspire
to and that's why I said right for most
of you watching this video I don't think
you have or I don't think you want to
just you know plow $250,000 into your
trading account right to trade the
markets and also that's assuming you
have a trading strategy a proven trading
strategy right that works right that
generates an average of 20% a
year now some of you might be thinking
but Raina you know I don't need $250,000
to start with you know Raina all I need
to do is to spend more time watching the
markets for more opportunities and boom
I make more profits right I can do
better than 20% a year R now I can do
500% a year righta I just need to watch
the markets for more
opportunities well sorry to bust your
bubble
but you know more screen time does not
equate to more profits why is that let
me explain trading is not like a job
right where you're trying to learn how
to grow some vegetables because if you
try to grow some vegetables okay let's
say you know you decided to be a
full-time vegetable farmer or whatever
you can probably first few months learn
how to you know grow the vegetables
learn what is fertilizer soil sunlight
water Etc and within a few months you
probably can successfully grow some
vegetables that is legitimate enough to
eat without poisoning yourself agree
yeah I think most people can do that but
trading is is different trading is not
like growing vegetables it's more like
trying to become a neurosurgeon okay so
can let me ask you can you successfully
do a brain surgery after a few months of
training probably not right you probably
turn someone's brain into mashed
potatoes yeah so there's a steep
learning curve right trying to be a
neurosurgeon you need to spend you know
a number of years in school become a
resident get more experience level up
further your studies and then maybe
after you know 12 15 years you become a
full-fledged
neurosurgeon okay so and it's the same
for trading there is a steep learning
curve involved but I can dare say that
trading it's not going to take you you
know 10 to 15 years to be a profitable
Trader in fact there are five stages to
profitable trading and I want to share
them with you right now so you can
better expect right uh what to expect so
the five stages to profitable trading
stage number one is this the hyper
newbie stage at this stage right this is
where you feel all excited about trading
you have high hopes right eager to learn
everything and anything that you can get
your depend on you know things like
Candlestick patterns price action
trading trend line support resistance
Etc okay and the more you learn the
higher you feel right the more excited
the higher you feel right it's like you
know taking drugs if you feel very high
whenever you Le you learn a new trading
strategies or
technique and during this stage right
you will come to a point where you
realize that you start blowing up
multiple trading accounts so you fund a
trading account could be a paper trading
account a live trading account and you
find yourself know blowing up this
trading account it turns into zero right
after a few trades and why is that and
when you realize that that's where you
move on to stage two which I call the
risk manager stage at this stage you
realize the importance of risk
management you realize that you can't
bet the farm on each trade it's probably
just 1% risk on each trade so this way
you know even if you lose on that trade
it's just an end bite so you learn how
to know calculate your position size Etc
and at this point right this is where
you st blowing up your trading account
but you face another problem now the
problem that you're facing is death by a
th000 cut so yeah you are managing your
risk yes you stop blowing up your
Trading account but your Equity curve
right the p&l in your account is going
in the wrong direction it's still going
down lower over time despite having
proper risk management and when you
realize that that's where you realize
that boom stage number three is this the
loan Ranger this is where you realize
the importance of having an H this is
the this is where you realize that you
must have a proven trading system that
works okay because you can have the best
risk management out there but without a
proven trading system that works you
will still eventually suffer death by a,
cut so at this stage you got to you know
get your hands dirty do the work like
you know back testing forward testing
know researching on trading strategies
and find something that works for you
and I think most Traders for me
personally I spent a lot of time in this
stage and if you do get out of this
stage this is where you move into the
fourth stage the profitable Trader stage
so at this stage you have found a
trading strategy that works for you and
you've been profitable over the last 12
months now at this stage right uh what
you realize is that yes you are
profitable Trader but when market
conditions change right your trading
strategy goes into a draw down it starts
to underperform in a given Market
condition that's where you realize man
you know it's not just enough to
be a Trader with just one trading
strategy you need to develop new trading
strategies that can tackle that can
handle or do well in different market
conditions and when you realize this
this is where you move into what I call
the fifth and final stage the business
owner stage where you treat trading as a
business where you continuously develop
new trading strategies so you can know
profit in different market
conditions as you can see right there
are five stages to profitable trading
and many Traders right they make the
mistake right of thinking that they can
quit their full-time job they're
probably at stage one or stage two at
best and then they can quickly jump to
stage four or stage five right after
they quit their full-time job their
mindset is that know by quitting their
full-time job they can accelerate their
learning curve right that's true yes you
can accelerate your learning curve
because you can spend more time uh
researching testing new ideas and stuff
like that but it comes with a cost and
let me explain what are some of this
cost right the first cost is that more
stress will lead you to make poor
trading decisions right so now question
is how does quitting your job make you
feel more stress and cause bad trading
decisions let me
explain when you quit your job you are
REM removing a fixed source of income
okay that fixed source of income but
here's the thing right trading doesn't
give you a fixed source of income as a
Trader you know some days you can make
money some days you can lose money some
weeks you can lose money even some
months you can lose money and depending
on the type of trading strategies that
you employ you can even lose money in a
given year okay so for example this is
one of the trading system that I teach
right in uh my program the ultimate
systems Trader program right so this
trading system is called a mean
reversion trading system you can see
that since 2000 over here right 2000 to
2024 right now this trading system has
been consistently profitable in the long
run over the last 20 plus years you know
bu Market bare Market whatever is making
money in the long run and if you were to
look at this trading system in more
details this is the results you can see
that on a given month on a given year
this system actually loses money so for
example in uh 2022 nothing to hide over
here this system actually lost 3.8% in
what year is this this is uh 2014 the
system lost 3% okay and if you look at
the individual months right in 2024 June
July August September this system
actually lost
money okay so imagine this right you
rely on your trading profits to put food
on the table to pay the
bills how stressful would that be right
because you will adopt the need to make
money syndrome right and when you have
the need to make money syndrome you make
poor trading decisions right for example
you make poor trading decisions
decisions like number one widen your
stop- loss right so so for example a
trade goes against you but you refuse to
take the loss you can't take the loss
because you know if you take a loss
right then you don't have enough money
right to pay your bills this month so
you widen your stop loss and guess what
the market somehow knows what you're
doing it reaches right the Widder the
the the further away stop loss that you
have set and eventually still hit that
stop loss and your loss is now bigger
than expected yeah or how about this you
average into your losses right so the
market goes against you you tell
yourself you know you know what I'm
going to average down into my losses
because if the market has a slight
bounce I could get out that break even
or maybe even a small profit let me
share with you a quick story right uh I
know of a Trader back then right uh in
my uh prop trading days right this
Trader right he was trading the Nik
Futures and he was he was long the Nik
Futures and after a few moments right he
was down about $2,000 so his mindset was
this okay I'm down $2,000 I'm a scalper
let me average into my losses right
because if the market has a slight
bounce which you know happens pretty
often right in the N back then you know
he could get out that break even or even
a small profit so aaging these losses
right he buy even more contracts and the
market continued to go against him he
went to the point where he was down
about $6,000 and the risk manager had
had no uh had no had no choice but you
know tap him on the shoulders and tell
him to cut his loss because his risk
limit is is brid yeah and the moment he
cut his loss guess what the market R
back in his favor he felt like an idiot
he you know smashed some stuff in the
office yeah so so here's the thing right
that's what happens right when you're
averaging into your losses right is that
you know you make the whole even bigger
right you make even poorer trading
decisions and it's it could right
especially when you have the need to
make money when you put foot on the
table when money is so essential you
make poor trading decisions like this or
how about this Revenge trading okay you
suffer one or two losses you cut those
loss but you quickly re-enter back new
positions new opportunities to try to
make back what you've lost earlier I
personally have experienced this in my
early years of trading I was trading
some simple breakout trading strategy
right whenever the price breaks up you
know you go along so I tried that
trading strategy I followed the rules
and the first two trades were losses and
my third trade guess what what
happened I didn't follow the rules I
simply you know create new rules right
because I saw new opportunities in the
market I was pretty much Revenge trading
trying to make back the earlier losses
that I suffered and those new trades
that I took were also losses and that
cycle just you know rins repeat itself
so all these poor trading decisions will
become a lot more apparent right when
you really need money to put foot on the
table when you quit your job your wealth
grows slower let me explain
so if you look at this imagine this you
have a $250,000 trading capital okay and
you earn 20% a year which is about
$50,000 a year and you withdraw all your
profits for you know to fund your
lifestyle pay the bills whatsoever now
let me ask you what's the size of your
account after 10
years well assuming that you know you
make $50,000 every year you withdraw all
the $50,000 every year the size of your
account will be the same
$250,000 and if you take into account
inflation right that $250 $50,000 is
clearly going to be a lot smaller right
compared to it today yeah so now what if
you have a full-time job or you have a
site gate or you run a business or
whatsoever and you don't need to
withdraw your
profits for your living how would that
change well if you look at this over
here this is a simple compound interest
calculator you start off with
$250,000 you grow your account for the
next 10 years at 20% annual return in
other words if your trading system does
an average of 20% you put here 20% okay
how how much would your account be worth
after 10 years well your account will be
worth drum roll get ready for it right $
1.5 million after 10 years compared with
$250,000 earlier can you see the
difference this is an opportunity cost
of like 1.3 million over 10 years and
what if some of you who have a full-time
job you have Surplus cash and you can
actually regularly add funds to your
trading account each year let's say you
know uh instead of adding $ Zer to your
account each year now because you have a
full-time job you can add in an extra
let's say $20,000 a year to your account
now how much would your account be worth
after 10 years right assuming again
you're growing it at an average annual
return of 20% well your account now will
be worth 2.1 million dollar that's the
opportunity cost right by not having a
full-time job or you know earning a
source of income somewhere else okay
because you decide to tr pursue trading
fulltime okay and by the way I'm just
giving you this example just projecting
based on the next 10 years if you do it
for 15 20 25 years the numbers will be
even larger the opportunity cost is
going to be that much greater to you
okay so think about
that so now the question
is should you quit your job to trade
full
time okay so a few things right if you
want to do it understand right the
freedom the flexibility well I'm not
sure if there's flexibility yeah there's
quite a bit of flexibility right the
freedom you cherish it a lot and it
might be worth even more than and just
you know dollars in your bank account so
here a few things to consider right if
you want to quit your job to trade
full-time number one make sure you have
sufficient trading Capital at least six
figures if you ask me at least if you're
based in Us in UK Singapore you need an
at least a six figures trading account
assuming you do an average of 20% a year
and you know
uh you have X doll to earn like you know
$40 $50,000 a year you know you probably
need like 200 to $250,000 to start with
of course if you can uh increase your
returns maybe instead of 20% % a year
you can do 30 40% a year 50% a year even
better right you don't need that much
large of a capital but I do not know
personally of any Trader who does you
know 50 60% a year consistently over the
last 10 years right so again uh manage
your expectations right you don't want
to be you know taking on more risk right
just to hit the percentage return
because what's going to happen is that
you will suffer a larger draw down and
might even blow up your trading account
means all your Capital go to zero and
that's even worse yeah so make sure you
have sufficient trading Capital number
two uh make sure your living expenses
for the next 12 months is at least
covered so this means that you have
funds that is not related to your
trading account these are funds right
that can support your leaving right
without taking from your trading account
this way no matter what happens in a
given day week month right you know that
your livelihood is not affected right
even though you might have a losing
month so the living expenses 12 months
of it covered somewhere aside from your
trading account so let's say on average
you spend I know $5,000 a month for your
living expenses maybe of a family or
whatsoever make sure you have at least
$60,000 set aside away from your trading
capital and finally you must have a
proven trading system that works right
you know you might have sufficient
Capital you know what to expect but if
your trading strategy doesn't work at
all and you think that you want to do it
full-time trying to figure out this
trading strategy as you go along then
guess what you're going to be you know
uh the opportunity cost is really great
I rather you do this research of trading
strategies to find the strategies that
suits you to find a trading strategies
that work while you have a full-time job
do it on the SES right do it while
you're working do it after work before
work on the weekend right so this way
the opportunity cost is a lot lesser for
you and by the way if you want to learn
such a trading strategy a proven trading
strategy that works Based on data
numbers spec testing then you you can
join me at my next uh event called stock
trading Secrets just go to my website
trading with r.com or and you click this
rate button or if you want to go to the
direct link it's just trading with r.com
STS right so during this two hour
webinar I will share with you a proven
stock trading system that has that works
right based on my own research and
testing generated about 3,225 right over
the last 22 years uh I will give you the
exact trading rules the entries the
setups the exits chart examples so this
way you know you can actually take that
system okay and you know trade it on
your own or make certain tweaks right
and then refine it to become your own I
recommend that approach actually so the
next event uh it's in November it's on a
weekday I believe the timing this time
around we can actually accommodate both
us UK people from Australia Singapore
right so this timing uh 7:30 to 9:30
p.m. Singapore time and during the
webinar we'll talk about you know the
fastest way to become a profitable
Trader even if you've tried everything
else and failed how to you know safely
and consistently grow your trading
account to six or seven figures and
Beyond even if you have a small starting
Capital how to profit in Boo and bare
markets even during a recession right so
all this and More in uh this webinar it
is free I'll put the link somewhere
below this uh video so you can sign up
for it with that it I wish you good luck
good trading I will talk to you soon